<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Bradshaws Bargain Biscuits</title>
    <link href="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com" />
    <updated>2024-02-21T14:13:28-06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Tommy Bradshaw</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://bradshawsbiscuits.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Experience the Joy of Homemade Biscuits with Gravy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tommy Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/experience-the-joy-of-homemade-biscuits-with-gravy/"/>
        <id>https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/experience-the-joy-of-homemade-biscuits-with-gravy/</id>
        <media:content url="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/8/biscuits-and-gravy.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Food"/>

        <updated>2024-02-21T14:13:28-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/8/biscuits-and-gravy.webp" alt="Yummy biscuits and gravy" />
                    Imagine a serene morning, the sun casting a warm glow through the kitchen window. The aroma of freshly baked biscuits fills the air, inviting a sense of comfort and joy. As you take the biscuits out of the oven, their golden-brown crust and soft, fluffy&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/8/biscuits-and-gravy.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Yummy biscuits and gravy" /></p>
                
  <p>
    <strong>Imagine a serene morning</strong>, the sun casting a warm glow through the kitchen window. The aroma of freshly baked biscuits fills the air, inviting a sense of comfort and joy. As you take the biscuits out of the oven, their golden-brown crust and soft, fluffy interior promise a delightful taste.
  </p>

  <p>
    Pairing these biscuits with the rich, creamy gravy creates a harmonious blend of flavors. The savory taste of the sausage gravy complements the buttery, tender biscuits perfectly. Sitting down to this meal, perhaps accompanied by a cup of your favorite coffee or tea, brings a moment of tranquility and satisfaction. It's a simple yet profound pleasure, a reminder of the joys found in the warmth of a homemade meal.
  </p>

  <p>
    This biscuit and gravy pairing is not just food; it's a manifestation of love and care, a nurturing way to start the day with a fulfilled heart and a satisfied palate.
  </p>

    <h2 id="homemade-biscuit-recipe">
      Homemade Biscuit Recipe
    </h2>

  <p>
    <strong>Here's a delightful homemade biscuit recipe</strong> that you can make with care and affection, perfect for a heartwarming morning experience. Paired with rich, savory gravy, these biscuits offer a comforting start to your day.
  </p>

    <h3 id="ingredients">
      Ingredients:
    </h3>

  <ul>
    <li>2 cups all-purpose flour
</li><li>1 tablespoon baking powder
</li><li>1 teaspoon salt
</li><li>1 tablespoon sugar (optional, for a touch of sweetness)
</li><li>1/3 cup unsalted butter, cold and cubed
</li><li>3/4 cup milk</li>
  </ul>

    <h3 id="instructions">
      Instructions:
    </h3>

  <ol>
    <li><strong>Preheat Oven:</strong> Start by preheating your oven to 425°F (220°C).
</li><li><strong>Dry Ingredients:</strong> In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, baking powder, salt, and sugar.
</li><li><strong>Butter:</strong> Add the cold, cubed butter to the dry ingredients. Use a pastry cutter or your fingers to blend the butter into the flour until the mixture resembles coarse crumbs.
</li><li><strong>Add Milk:</strong> Gradually stir in the milk until the dough pulls away from the sides of the bowl.
</li><li><strong>Knead Dough:</strong> Turn the dough out onto a floured surface and knead gently 3-4 times.
</li><li><strong>Roll &amp; Cut: </strong>Roll the dough to about 1-inch thickness. Cut biscuits with a biscuit cutter or a floured glass.
</li><li><strong>Bake:</strong> Place biscuits on an ungreased baking sheet and bake for 13-15 minutes or until golden brown.</li>
  </ol>

    <h2 id="serving-with-gravylessbrgreater">
      Serving with Gravy<br>
    </h2>

    <h3 id="ingredients">
      Ingredients:
    </h3>

  <ul>
    <li>1 pound sausage (your choice of mild or spicy)
</li><li>1/3 cup all-purpose flour
</li><li>3 to 4 cups milk
</li><li>Salt and pepper to taste</li>
  </ul>

    <h3 id="instructions">
      Instructions:
    </h3>

  <ol>
    <li><strong>Cook Sausage: </strong>In a large skillet, cook the sausage over medium heat until browned and crumbly.
</li><li><strong>Make Roux:</strong> Sprinkle the flour over the sausage and stir until blended.
</li><li><strong>Add Milk:</strong> Gradually add the milk, stirring constantly, until the mixture comes to a slight boil. Reduce the heat and simmer until thickened.
</li><li><strong>Season:</strong> Add salt and pepper to taste.</li>
  </ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Creating Great Biscuit Recipes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tommy Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/creating-great-biscuit-recipes/"/>
        <id>https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/creating-great-biscuit-recipes/</id>
        <media:content url="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/patrick-fore-16Vfy9BfLio-unsplash-1.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Musings"/>

        <updated>2024-01-16T01:13:54-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/patrick-fore-16Vfy9BfLio-unsplash-1.jpg" alt="Great biscuits come from great recipes" />
                    In the early hours of dawn, the bakers' hands craft the essence of morning joy. They all dance in a ballet of baking bliss. Golden biscuits rise like the sun, each layer a testament to the art of breakfast. The aroma of freshly baked dough&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/patrick-fore-16Vfy9BfLio-unsplash-1.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Great biscuits come from great recipes" /></p>
                
  <p>
    <strong>In the early hours of dawn</strong>, the bakers' hands craft the essence of morning joy.
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>Flour&nbsp;</li><li>Butter&nbsp;</li><li>Sugar</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    <strong>They all dance</strong> in a ballet of baking bliss. Golden biscuits rise like the sun, each layer a testament to the art of breakfast. The aroma of freshly baked dough intertwines with hints of vanilla, creating a symphony of scents that awaken the sleepiest of souls. In this realm, every crumb tells a story of warmth and comfort.
  </p>

    <h2 id="set-ovens-to-bake">
      Set Ovens to Bake!
    </h2>

  <p>
    <strong>As the oven hums</strong> its harmonious tune, the bakers weave their magic. Rolling pins glide over dough, shaping dreams of flaky perfection. Each biscuit, a canvas of culinary craftsmanship, waits patiently to become the star of the breakfast table. Here, in the heart of the bakery, time pauses, savoring the anticipation of the first bite. This is where the alchemy of flour, butter, and love transforms the mundane into the extraordinary.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash.jpg" height="1280" width="1920" alt="Bakery artists working dough "  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/responsive/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash-xs.jpg 300w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/responsive/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash-sm.jpg 480w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/responsive/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash-md.jpg 768w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/responsive/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/responsive/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/4/responsive/theme-photos-Hx7xdwhj2AY-unsplash-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    <strong>Beneath the morning's amber glow</strong>, the kitchen comes alive with the ballet of baking. Eggs and milk, companions in culinary creation, join the chorus of ingredients serenading the senses. Crisp bacon whispers secrets to golden-brown scones, while the coffee pot sings a robust melody. In this haven, each biscuit is not just a morsel, but a masterpiece, embodying the soul of the baker and the spirit of the morning.
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    <em>The art of breakfast reaches its crescendo as the biscuits emerge, triumphant, from the oven.</em>
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    <em>Each one, a golden dome of delight, cradles the promise of a new day</em>.
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    <em>The butter melts in a cascade of richness, and the jam adds its sweet, fruity chorus.</em>
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    <em>Here, in the sacred dance of flour and fire, lies the essence of morning's joy.</em>
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    <em>The table is set, the feast of dawn awaits, a celebration of simplicity and splendor.</em>
  </p>

  <p>
    <strong>As the day unfolds</strong>, the memory of breakfast lingers. The echo of the bakery's warmth, the tender flakiness of the biscuits, and the comforting embrace of a well-crafted meal resonate in the heart. In this world of baking, biscuits, and breakfast, each bite is a journey, a voyage through the senses, a tribute to the timeless tradition of breaking bread at dawn. And thus, the cycle begins anew, in anticipation of tomorrow's treasures from the oven.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>
<hr class="separator separator--long-line" />

  <p class="align-center">
    <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baking" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Baking</a> | <a href="https://www.kingarthurbaking.com/recipes/buttermilk-biscuits-recipe" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Biscuits</a> | <a href="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/live-music-wednesdays/">Music</a>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Live Music Wednesdays!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tommy Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/live-music-wednesdays/"/>
        <id>https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/live-music-wednesdays/</id>
        <media:content url="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3/rob-simmons-lWHP55X-biA-unsplash-1.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="News"/>
            <category term="Events"/>

        <updated>2024-01-15T16:59:02-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3/rob-simmons-lWHP55X-biA-unsplash-1.jpg" alt="Playing Folk Music at Bradshaw&#x27;s Bargain Biscuits" />
                    Come on out to Bradshaw's and experience live folk music Wednesday mornings. Every Wednesday this summer we will have a local folk music group here at the restaurant sharing their craft with you as you enjoy our craft: Biscuits! Here is the line up -&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3/rob-simmons-lWHP55X-biA-unsplash-1.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Playing Folk Music at Bradshaw&#x27;s Bargain Biscuits" /></p>
                <p>Come on out to Bradshaw's and experience live folk music Wednesday mornings.  Every Wednesday this summer we will have a local <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folk_music" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">folk music</a> group here at the restaurant sharing their craft with you as you enjoy our craft: Biscuits!</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//stage.jpg" alt="Empty stage for folk art musing at Bradshaw's Bargain Biscuits" width="640" height="427" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//responsive/stage-xs.jpg 300w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//responsive/stage-sm.jpg 480w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//responsive/stage-md.jpg 768w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//responsive/stage-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//responsive/stage-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://bradshawsbiscuits.com/media/posts/3//responsive/stage-2xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<p>Here is the line up - you will not want to miss it:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Oak &amp; Ivy Harmony </strong> - June 1</li>
<li><strong>The Meadowlark Minstrels</strong> - June 8</li>
<li><strong>The Riverside Ramblers</strong> - June 15</li>
<li><strong>Crimson Clover Collective</strong> - June 22</li>
<li>TBD - June 29</li>
<li><strong>Pinecone Poets</strong> - July 6</li>
<li><strong>Harmony Hollow</strong> - July 13</li>
<li>TBD - July 20</li>
<li><strong>The Wandering Whippoorwills</strong> - July 27</li>
<li><strong>Willow Creek Quartet</strong> - Aug 3</li>
</ul>
<p>Here is what people are saying about the experience:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Last week at Bradshaw's, The Riverside Ramblers took us on an unforgettable musical journey. Their blend of soulful folk melodies and foot-tapping rhythms perfectly complemented the homely atmosphere of our restaurant. Each song they performed was a masterpiece of storytelling, rich with emotion and the spirit of folk tradition. Their music, as comforting and heartwarming as our signature biscuits, left our customers enchanted and asking for more.</p>
<p>Krystal - Henderson, KY</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Harmony Hollow's performance at Bradshaw's was nothing short of magical. Their unique fusion of traditional folk with modern undertones was the perfect soundtrack for an evening of good food and great company. Their charismatic presence and engaging melodies created a lively yet intimate atmosphere. Customers were not only treated to the best biscuits in town but also to a musical experience that touched their souls and lifted their spirits.</p>
<p>Edward - Evansville, IN</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Be sure to join us Wednesday for music and the best biscuits north of the Ohio river!  Don't know where we are, have never had a Bradshaw's biscuit? - <a href="https://t.ly/P9lln" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Visit us here today!</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
